<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-04-22T17:57:48-06:00</updated><id>https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ryan P. Randall</title><subtitle>&quot;Ryan P. Randall's website, with his Ph.D. student and community college librarian blog&quot;</subtitle><entry><title type="html">August 2020 Monthly Signal Boost</title><link href="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/monthly-signal-boost/august-2020-monthly-signal-boost" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="August 2020 Monthly Signal Boost" /><published>2020-08-31T13:34:53-06:00</published><updated>2020-08-31T13:34:53-06:00</updated><id>https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/monthly-signal-boost/august-2020-monthly-signal-boost</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/monthly-signal-boost/august-2020-monthly-signal-boost">&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/monthly-signal-boost/introducing-monthly-signal-boosts&quot;&gt;Monthly What?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2020 has not been a kind year. This last month has been hectic and at times very overwhelming. Here’s some of what has worked to keep my spirits up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mindfulness&quot;&gt;Mindfulness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to get back into mindfulness &amp;amp; meditation practices, since I’d like to more skillfully recognize when my mind or emotions wander to realms I’d prefer they not go. It’s also good practice at finding joy in small things, to better recharge and practice the hopefulness necessary to keep doing difficult things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve only listened to the first few practices of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wakingup.com&quot;&gt;Waking Up&lt;/a&gt; app by &lt;a href=&quot;https://samharris.org&quot;&gt;Sam Harris&lt;/a&gt;, but it seems like a great fit for anyone interested in mindfulness practices—and particularly anyone of a more analytical bent. Tai chi (offered as &lt;a href=&quot;http://dotaichi.com&quot;&gt;P.E. classes&lt;/a&gt; at UC Riverside!) was the first way I was able to connect with a mindfulness practice in a sustained way. I think this was largely because the slow physical exercises kept my ADHD tendencies occupied &lt;em&gt;just enough&lt;/em&gt; to help me also pay attention to my breath, my sensations, and whatever else entered into my attention. Waking Up is the mindfulness instruction I’ve encountered that’s closest my experience of learning moving mediation though tai chi, largely because of how deftly Harris blends his verbal instructions with periods of silence to help you experience what he presents. I’m not sure yet if a subscription would be right for me, but I definitely recommend trying the first few (free!) days of the app if you’ve been curious about mindfulness. That’s especially true if you’ve tried mindfulness previously but were turned off by some aspects how it was taught. Harris’s approach seems resolutely non-religious and non-spiritual/mystical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://plumvillage.app&quot;&gt;Plum Village&lt;/a&gt; app, on the other hand, clearly centers mindfulness practices in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Engaged_Buddhism&quot;&gt;engaged Buddhist&lt;/a&gt; approach of &lt;a href=&quot;https://plumvillage.app/thich-nhat-hanh/&quot;&gt;Thích Nhất Hạnh&lt;/a&gt;. The app is entirely free and features guided meditations, other practices, texts, and more from the Plum Village community. If you’ve previously encountered the original version of the app (released back in 2018), the newest versions (up to 2.2 as of mid-August) are greatly expanded and refined. I can’t speculate what it would be like to learn mindfulness or Buddhist practices primarily through this app, but I definitely appreciate what the Plum Village community has made available through it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;music&quot;&gt;Music&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jukebouncewerk.bandcamp.com/track/love-genius&quot;&gt;Love Genius&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://jukebouncewerk.bandcamp.com&quot;&gt;Sonic D&lt;/a&gt; has consistently brought a goofy grin to my face since the first time I heard it. It’s a footwork / bass music version of a Tom Tom Club tune you might recognize through a bunch of songs that sample or remix it—in particular Mariah Carey’s “Fantasy.” You might also dig some of his other stuff, such as what he’s got on &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/sncd&quot;&gt;Soundcloud&lt;/a&gt; or his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.empirednb.com/shows/mathnscience&quot;&gt;Math &amp;amp; Science&lt;/a&gt; mixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://johntejada.bandcamp.com/album/time-flex&quot;&gt;Time Flex&lt;/a&gt; is basically a compilation of early releases by &lt;a href=&quot;https://johntejada.bandcamp.com&quot;&gt;John Tejada&lt;/a&gt; under the moniker Autodidact. Originally released in 1996 &amp;amp; 1997, these tunes have more of a Warp Records / Polygon Window vibe than Tejada’s later stuff. If you’ve ever wanted something like Polygon Window but with more groove &amp;amp; shuffle, this will be right up your alley.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ryan</name></author><category term="monthly-signal-boost" /><summary type="html">Mindfulness with the Waking Up and Plum Village apps; Most excellent tunes from Sonic D and Autodidact</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SIFT Links</title><link href="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/sift-links" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SIFT Links" /><published>2020-07-29T13:34:53-06:00</published><updated>2020-07-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/sift-links</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/sift-links">&lt;p&gt;Here are some links related to my submission to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://flipgrid.com/93f8f2f7&quot;&gt;“innovative ideas” lightning talk / virtual poster session&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://libraries.idaho.gov/moss2020/&quot;&gt;2020 MOSS Meetup&lt;/a&gt; organized by ICfL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-sift-moves&quot;&gt;The SIFT Moves&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hapgood.us/2019/05/12/sift-and-a-check-please-preview/&quot;&gt;Introducing SIFT, a Four Moves Acronym&lt;/a&gt;, Mike Caulfield’s initial post about the moves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notion.so/Check-Please-Starter-Course-ae34d043575e42828dc2964437ea4eed&quot;&gt;Check, Please! Course&lt;/a&gt;, an OER textbook with explanations and demonstrations of the moves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Caulfield’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://infodemic.blog&quot;&gt;SIFTing through the Pandemic&lt;/a&gt; applies the moves to claims about COVID-19&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sift-moves-at-cwi&quot;&gt;SIFT Moves at CWI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a couple components of “Source Sifter,” a badge in the CWI “Research Basics Badge Set”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/t4clt0c43X8&quot;&gt;Evaluating Sources with the SIFT Moves Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1vyugivoc0ZdnpxSaLJkrCL22LW82HVMyoC4gXNJ6kNQ/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;SIFT Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;related-links&quot;&gt;Related Links&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mike Caulfield’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://webliteracy.pressbooks.com&quot;&gt;Web Literacy for Student Fact-Checkers&lt;/a&gt;, an OER textbook that predated &amp;amp; lead to the SIFT moves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/wFN6XNawUMU&quot;&gt;SIFT vs CRAAP video&lt;/a&gt; for instructors at CWI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>ryan</name></author><category term="conferences" /><category term="pedagogy" /><summary type="html">Links related to a lightning talk for the 2020 MOSS Meetup about our switch from the CRAAP test to the SIFT moves.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">July 2020 Monthly Signal Boost</title><link href="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/monthly-signal-boost/july-2020-monthly-signal-boost" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="July 2020 Monthly Signal Boost" /><published>2020-07-05T13:34:53-06:00</published><updated>2020-07-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/monthly-signal-boost/july-2020-monthly-signal-boost</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/monthly-signal-boost/july-2020-monthly-signal-boost">&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/monthly-signal-boost/introducing-monthly-signal-boosts&quot;&gt;Monthly What?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;podcasts&quot;&gt;Podcasts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://organizingideaspod.wordpress.com/2020/02/28/ep-20-libraries-and-disabilities-with-jessica-schomberg/&quot;&gt;Organizing Ideas Podcast: Episode 20 with Jessica Schomberg&lt;/a&gt; Jessica Schomberg talks about their &lt;a href=&quot;https://litwinbooks.com/books/beyond-accommodation/&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;, other readings they’ve learned from, how workplace improvements for disabled folks will lead to better workplaces for everyone, about relationships and solidarity in library work. It’s a really engaging listen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/thelatinocard/mask-culinity&quot;&gt;The Latino Card: Episode — Mask-ulinity&lt;/a&gt; Talking about different approaches people are taking to social distancing. Discusses ?Tommy Simmons? article at the Idaho Press, which talks about psychology of adhering to government guidelines. How wearing a mask is a signal to the world that COVID19 is a problem &amp;amp; we need to work together on addressing it. Masculinity and admitting vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/ep-6-with-abraham-lateiner-of-freedom-beyond/id1495723247?i=1000466133862&quot;&gt;The Better Bozo: Episode 6&lt;/a&gt; I wasn’t sure about listening to this whole episode for the first few minutes, since it sounded a little too much like listening in on a sporpsball conversation or general talk radio. But it ended up featuring a fascinating discussion about how privileged white guys can get better at asking themselves “who benefits by me staying silent at this moment?”, as well as how to apply organizing principles to help forward collective liberation. One portion that seems particularly relevant to library work is when the guest, Abraham Lateiner of Freedom Beyond!, mentions that it’s important to be attuned to both the macro and micro levels in a situation, as well as the tension between two poles. (Apparently polarity work is an organizing tool?) The main polarized tension he discusses is between challenge and affirmation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He uses the example of how America has praised individual freedoms for so long that it’s become incredibly difficult to champion equitable outcomes. As I’m typing this, I can’t help but wonder what an ALA Office of Intellectual Responsibility would look like, or even an ALA Office of Intellectual Equity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;articles&quot;&gt;Articles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tricycle.org/trikedaily/recognize-racism/&quot;&gt;“Starting Points”&lt;/a&gt; by Andrew Cooper was written for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buddhistpeacefellowship.org&quot;&gt;Buddhist Peace Fellowship&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;em&gt;Turning Wheel&lt;/em&gt; magazine in 1993, on the second anniversary of the beating of Rodney King. Cooper explains, “The question is not whether or not a community is ‘racist’—the question is how this racism operates.” He also quotes a psychiatrist’s explanation that “in the human realm, the law of survival is not kill or be killed; it is define or be defined.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was living in Riverside and in high school for the King verdict and the uprisings, all of which were very much huge local news. Witnessing such a wanton failure of the legal system to produce justice profoundly influenced my understanding of our legal, social, economic, representational, and other systems. This article encapsulates a lot about those systems into surprisingly few words. As we still seek to improve upon these current systems, it’s an article well worth your time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ryan</name></author><category term="monthly-signal-boost" /><summary type="html">Organizing Ideas Podcast; The Latino Card; Tricycle Magazine; etc.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing Monthly Signal Boosts</title><link href="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/monthly-signal-boost/introducing-monthly-signal-boosts" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing Monthly Signal Boosts" /><published>2020-07-01T13:34:53-06:00</published><updated>2020-07-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/monthly-signal-boost/introducing-monthly-signal-boosts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/monthly-signal-boost/introducing-monthly-signal-boosts">&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-this-about&quot;&gt;What’s This About?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty clear that my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryanpatrickrandall.com/categories/#weekly-assemblage&quot;&gt;weekly assemblage posts&lt;/a&gt; aren’t particularly sustainable, at least at the moment. All the same, I want to get back to regular posts. With these I aim at boosting—sometimes also critiquing—things that I appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing &lt;a href=&quot;https://schomj.weebly.com&quot;&gt;Jessica Schomberg’s Monthly Reading Lists&lt;/a&gt; gave me the idea to do a monthly format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll see where this goes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-will-they-work&quot;&gt;How Will They Work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m really good at reading and engaging widely—but I’m not as great at keeping notes or forcing myself to reflect. So I’ll experiment with the exact way I’ll annotate or respond to what I mention in these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m planning to start a post at the beginning of each month, then edit it throughout the month. So each will be a monthly log, pretty much, of stuff I want to amplify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-that-it&quot;&gt;Is That It?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’m writing this introduction to these posts, I’m also working on putting together my dissertation qualifying exam lists. I’m intrigued by the ethos / approach of working in public, so I’m considering doing some sort of &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.andymatuschak.org/z3SjnvsB5aR2ddsycyXofbYR7fCxo7RmKW2be?stackedNotes=z4SDCZQeRo4xFEQ8H4qrSqd68ucpgE6LU155C&quot;&gt;“evergreen notes”&lt;/a&gt;—most likely a set of pages that I continually edit as I refine ideas, definitions, connections, bibliographies, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure quite yet how that sort of note will live on my site, but again: we’ll find out!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ryan</name></author><category term="monthly-signal-boost" /><summary type="html">Monthly signal boosts will be short reflections on what I've read, listened to, watch, etc.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ah, Carl, while you are not safe I am not safe</title><link href="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/while-you-are-not-safe-i-am-not-safe" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ah, Carl, while you are not safe I am not safe" /><published>2020-02-23T11:34:53-07:00</published><updated>2020-07-03T19:50:00-06:00</updated><id>https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/while-you-are-not-safe-i-am-not-safe</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/while-you-are-not-safe-i-am-not-safe">&lt;h2 id=&quot;braiding-together-a-few-strands-of-thought&quot;&gt;Braiding Together a Few Strands of Thought&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post was prompted by a few things I saw on Mastodon and Twitter, plus having wanted to write something during LIS Mental Health Week for a few years now. I started drafting it as a short thread that brought in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/medicine-and-dentistry/social-model-of-disability&quot;&gt;social model of disability&lt;/a&gt; as a response to @chaotic_kat’s thread, then things sort of snowballed, and here we are! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a good chance I’ll tweak this post further, but I want to share it before the last day of this year’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyurl.com/lismentalhealth20&quot;&gt;LIS Mental Health Week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of our mental starting points include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I saw the best minds of my generation destroyed by austerity&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Sarah Osment (@sm_osment) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sm_osment/status/1231051671469535232?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 22, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case that “Howl” allusion and the one in this post’s title don’t leap out at you, you might want to take the time to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/49303/howl&quot;&gt;read it&lt;/a&gt; and its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/54163/footnote-to-howl&quot;&gt;related “footnote” poem&lt;/a&gt;. Ideally read them aloud, as incandescently or woefully as you’d like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Hey &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ADHD?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#ADHD&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/neurodiversesquad?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#neurodiversesquad&lt;/a&gt; - I want to talk about how stigma, lack of education &amp;amp; support, and toxic masculinity has affected the the ADHD men in my life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thread&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; #DREADPirate Kat B 🏳️‍🌈 (@chaotic_kat) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chaotic_kat/status/1169688745387233280?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;September 5, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was diagnosed with ADHD by third or fourth grade, i.e. the later 1980s—and a bunch of that thread rings true for me. The bits that resonate most are years of hiding my diagnosis, avoiding meds/accommodations, later repeated bouts of shame/anxiety/depression, struggling to maintain friendships, etc. A lot of those negative things have been far worse for my cousins—and I believe my parents were a crucial difference in our experiences of all this because they gave me an early understanding of the social model of disability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C.:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://meredith.wolfwater.com/wordpress/2020/02/18/lismentalhealth-that-time-my-brain-and-my-job-tried-to-kill-me/&quot;&gt;Meredith Wolfwater’s piece&lt;/a&gt; about a toxic workplace and how she’s worked to change herself since leaving it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meredith’s post reminds me a lot of the grad program I was in before taking the route of librarianship. I’m still not ready to write about my experiences in that program in much depth—basically, it was fantastic, right up until it was the opposite. For now, it’ll suffice to say that I’m not particularly good at reading internal politics—and that I was particularly unprepared to navigate having a couple of “advisors” who never gave advice about my project or substantive feedback on the contents of my project, only reminders that time was passing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;social-model-of-disability&quot;&gt;Social Model of Disability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I said above that my parents helped mitigate the negative aspects of unmedicated ADHD, I mean that I 💯 lucked out by having special ed &amp;amp; d/Deaf educators as parents. The social model of disability influenced a lot of our talks, their emotional support, their “hey, let’s see if this technique helps” encouragement, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I don’t remember my parents using the phrase “the social model of disability,” they often talked about how deafness, blindness, and other perceptual impairments are not inherently barriers in and of themselves. Instead, these impairments become “disabilities” due to way we’ve built social and material structures without accounting &amp;amp; preparing for these differences. The social and material exclusion people with impairments face becomes physical and social oppression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up around schools for the Deaf and Blind also meant that I was constantly around children and adults with very different abilities and ways of interacting than my own, getting to partake in their joy at dances and basketball games, where sound pressure and bass &amp;amp; drum vibrations helped everyone keep time or rally in support of their teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bringing this back around to @chaotic_kat’s thread on toxic masculinity and what parents can do to help support children they expect to be neurodivergent, I believe my early internalization of the social model of disability profoundly lessened how much power ADHD stigma has had over my mental health. It meant that I never bought in to the notion that just “trying harder” was an adequate or appropriate answer to things. I recognized that I was different, even if the 1980s &amp;amp; 1990s discourse around ADHD didn’t understand the broader range of how my differences would manifest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is what also primed me to see the structural/social aspects of toxic masculinity by early high school. Reading Fugazi lyrics, riot grrrl, Sassy &amp;amp; Dirt magazines, having a group of weirdo friends, etc also didn’t hurt, of course—and I also didn’t have those words for it yet. But between my own dad’s example of kindness and the cultural questioning of “tough guy” poses (&lt;a href=&quot;https://genius.com/Fugazi-bulldog-front-lyrics&quot;&gt;“your bulldog front”&lt;/a&gt;), it was increasingly clear that there are many ways of being a guy in the world—although many of the commons ways of doing so are toxic to others and oneself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This social model made it way easier for me to get how race, gender, sexuality, class, etc often are linked to material structures of oppression, not just simple “differences” without consequences or histories. Knowing that model isn’t sufficient, of course. And I now know first hand that it’s nowhere the same as actually taking meds, getting accommodations, etc. But knowing and internalizing that model leads more rapidly to solidarity, to coalitional thinking, to working to make more accessible websites, conferences, classrooms, workplaces, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the social model alone &lt;strong&gt;doesn’t&lt;/strong&gt; overcome my deep Gen X knowledge that every institution—even &amp;amp; especially ones you love, like that grad program—will betray you, that any disclosure or first-hand advocacy can nudge that betrayal machinery into motion if it hasn’t already started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But “ah, Carl, while you are not safe I am not safe”—so I need to be louder about my experiences, my joys, frustrations, and ways of being in the world, since that kind of coalition building across differences and identities is what will help dismantle the structures of oppression that continue diminishing and hurting neurodivergent folks, folks with mental health issues, folks from communities with racial, ethnic, or sexual identities that have been historically oppressed, etc. Collectively &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.mtu.edu/~jdslack/readings/CSReadings/Hall_Old_and_New_Identities_Ethnicities.pdf&quot;&gt;creating new identities&lt;/a&gt; like “neurodiverse” is one way of negotiating and advocating for justice, both for ourselves &amp;amp; for others. This kind of coalitional work is indeed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/oclc/1022312889&quot;&gt;how we get free&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;poetry--other-infrastructures-of-support&quot;&gt;Poetry &amp;amp; Other Infrastructures of Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raincrossunderground.omeka.net/items/show/2&quot;&gt;Riverside Underground Poetry Organization&lt;/a&gt; in many ways got me through the depression of not being in school after undergrad, then through the anxiety of being back in grad school. An all ages open mic held in the basement of a coffeeshop owned by Darren (a gay Black man, whom I had the pleasure of interviewing for my high school newspaper the summer he opened the place), it’s one of the more radically inclusive communities I’ve been part of—even though I now realize the problems posed by the lack of physical accessibility to this kind of basement event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The open mics offered an infrastructure for questioning society’s expectations and boundaries, a platform for performing multiple facets of your being in the span of three pieces or 10 minutes, whichever came first. That community carried me and others through quite a few years of ups and downs, heartbreaks and breakdowns and elations and achievements. I didn’t realize how much the loss of that community would affect me when I followed a professor’s recommendation to uproot myself and move across the country for a different program—I figured that something akin to that &lt;strong&gt;simply must exist&lt;/strong&gt; in other towns, since Southern California dumps on Riverside and the greater Inland Empire constantly for being a cultural backwater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fred Moten &amp;amp; Stefano Harney write a lot about study in their book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.minorcompositions.info/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/undercommons-web.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Undercommons: Fugitive Planning and Black Study&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I’ll readily admit that I’m still figuring out what they mean by study, by debt, and by many of the other terms in that book. But to the extent I feel I understand “study” as a mode of collective questioning and relating to others outside of individuating institutions like academia, those open mic nights and the group of us who milled about and asked questions, shared drinks and embraces and tears and pitched in for gas and for rent, who carried each other through hard times and cheered at each others’ achievements and performances… that’s a model for questioning our current world and finding ways toward a better one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post doesn’t have a tidy conclusion—and I’m not sure it should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m mostly just giving thanks and expressing solidarity with the #NeurodiverseSquad folks, with the LIS Mental Health Week people, with #critlib, and with the other online communities I learn from constantly. Although we’re distributed across the internet instead of sitting on the ground in a basement, these communities have become part of who I think with and for, who provide me much-needed models for subverting the status quo, for opening up new mental, physical, social, and technical spaces of possibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ryan</name></author><category term="neurodiversity" /><category term="LISMentalHealth" /><category term="a11y" /><summary type="html">The social model of disability offers insights into society, differences, and oppressive structures beyond disability.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ALA Annual 2018: My Schedule, Our Notes</title><link href="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/my-ala-annual-2018-schedule" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ALA Annual 2018: My Schedule, Our Notes" /><published>2018-06-19T12:34:53-06:00</published><updated>2018-06-19T12:34:53-06:00</updated><id>https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/my-ala-annual-2018-schedule</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/my-ala-annual-2018-schedule">&lt;h2 id=&quot;alaac2018&quot;&gt;#ALAAC2018&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t been to an Annual ALA Conference yet, so it’ll be interesting to see how my attention can hold up to meeting so many people and hearing so many ideas. I’ve been to a number of smaller conferences, but nothing on this scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://oasis.sandstorm.io/shared/FtfUzJBeY_PW_tNa-1WPCxD-sONAqiUU9X5ZUvC19Dn&quot;&gt;Critical ALA Annual 2018&lt;/a&gt; list of “sessions of possible interest to critical library workers” made by Eamon Tewell and others, here’s a schedule of where I intend to be while in NOLA. I’ll do my best to update this throughout the week, so we can try to meet up if you’d like. Messaging me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.social/@foureyedsoul&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/foureyedsoul&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; would be great ways to get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll do my best to always have an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inthelibrarywiththeleadpipe.org/about/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the Library with the Lead Pipe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; button on my backpack or lanyard to make it easier to spot me. Please feel free to chat about the journal’s submission or open peer review processes, talk about ideas you have, or anything else. I’ll bring a few buttons with the journal logo’s to give away as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/assets/images/lpLogoButton.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;In the Library with the Lead Pipe logo button&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll probably also bring a small number of earplugs. So if you plan to go out dancing or if you see me out somewhere loud, ask and I might have some for you &amp;amp; your ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;group-note-taking--live-tweeting&quot;&gt;Group Note-taking &amp;gt; Live Tweeting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a growing practice of shared note-taking at unconferences and conferences, like at &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/0B6Obmnl0RQwTWWFXYld0Vkhvcmc?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;CLAPS2016&lt;/a&gt; and at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://critlib2017.wordpress.com/program/&quot;&gt;#critlib Unconference 2017&lt;/a&gt; in Baltimore. Let’s keep that going and try using more privacy-respecting platforms this time around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in helping take group notes—which seem like a more hospitable format than live tweeting for many of us—I’m planning to make publicly-editable &lt;a href=&quot;http://etherpad.org&quot;&gt;Etherpad&lt;/a&gt; notes hosted at &lt;a href=&quot;https://riseup.net&quot;&gt;RiseUp&lt;/a&gt;. It’ll be like shared Google Docs, only on a platform that helps avoid Google’s many privacy-destroying tentacles. :octopus: :thumbsdown:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plan is to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;task-list&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strike&gt;[x] make a pad for each session I'll attend @done &lt;/strike&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strike&gt;[x] give each pad a 1 year lifespan (which anyone can do as they create a pad) @done &lt;/strike&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strike&gt;[x] link to those pads here @done &lt;/strike&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;ultimately move our collectively-written notes somewhere else to be determined, such as my site or maybe something like a Sandstorm.io instance for library workers and/or other folks interested in #critlib-type things.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:sandpie&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:sandpie&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can think of a better process or make other pads/notes that you want added to shared list, let me know on &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.social/@foureyedsoul&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/foureyedsoul&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, please: &lt;strong&gt;if there’s a microphone, always use the microphone.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-schedule&quot;&gt;My Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thursday&quot;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m flying in today—and I wish I could be listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kexp.org/read/2018/5/10/announcing-public-enemy-album-breakdown/&quot;&gt;KEXP’s breakdown of Public Enemy’s &lt;em&gt;It Takes a Nation of Millions to Hold Us Back&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; while in flight. Hopefully they record it or at least spell out the playlist somewhere. &lt;em&gt;Fear of a Black Planet&lt;/em&gt; was much more formative for me but I’d love to learn anything I could about the Bomb Squad’s production process for any of their albums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might be down to meet up for vegetarian/vegan food, coffee, or other stuff this evening. Let me know!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;friday&quot;&gt;Friday&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning &amp;amp; early afternoon I’ll be exploring NOLA and the convention center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:00p–2:00pm:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com/2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=380901&quot;&gt;(NMRT) Annual Conference Orientation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/ALAAC2018Fri0100pmNewMembers-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:00pm–5:30pm:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=405586&quot;&gt;Opening General Session featuring Michelle Obama&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/ALAAC2018Fri0400pm-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:30pm–6:30pm:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=400110&quot;&gt;Meet the Authors: Mariko Tamaki and Shea Fontana&lt;/a&gt; (most likely)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;saturday&quot;&gt;Saturday&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9:00am–10:00am:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=352598&quot;&gt;Making the Framework Work: Adapting the ACRL Framework for Information Literacy in Community College Library Instruction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/CAIs6xumpU3Z-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:30am–11:30am:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=380846&quot;&gt;Student Learning and Information Literacy Committee Discussion Forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/hEqgaJDiNPSg-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:00pm–2:30pm:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=353518&quot;&gt;(LIRT) Moving Beyond the Threshold: Next Steps in Critical Information Literacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/kK7pf0E4icCG-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:30pm–3:30pm:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=352254&quot;&gt;Building Inclusion: How Can Research Instruction at Two-Year Colleges Help Students Successfully Transition to the University?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/ALAAC2018Sat230p-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:00pm–5:00pm:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=352459&quot;&gt;New Librarians on the Block: Early Career Librarianship, Management, and Leadership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/ALAAC2018Sat0400pm-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sunday&quot;&gt;Sunday&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9:00am–10:00am:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=352608&quot;&gt;High Impact Librarianship: A Showcase of Collaborative and Experiential Learning Initiatives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/ALAAC2018Sun0900am-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:30am–11:30am:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=352589&quot;&gt;Whiteness in LIS: Tracing its Impact, Mapping Resistance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/ALAAC2018Sun1030am-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12:00pm–1:00pm:&lt;br /&gt;
In the Library in the Lead Pipe meet up in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.alaannual.org/whats-happening/networking-uncommons&quot;&gt;Networking Uncommons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:30pm–3:30pm:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=352249&quot;&gt;Breaking Below the Surface of Racism, Whiteness, and Implicit Bias&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/ALAAC2018Sun0230pm-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:00pm–5:00pm:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=352251&quot;&gt;Bridging the Gap: Supporting Subject Liaisons to Become Ambassadors for Digital Scholarship in Academic Libraries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/ALAAC2018Sun0400pm-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;OR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=352471&quot;&gt;Neutrality and Its Discontents: Exploring the Ethics of Librarianship in a Partisan World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/ALAAC2018Sun0400pmNeutrality-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;OR MORE LIKELY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
4:30om–5:30pm:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=380758&quot;&gt;Progressive Librarians Guild Meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:00pm–8:00pm:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/244714849439515/&quot;&gt;GLBT Round Table Social&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;OR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=380478&quot;&gt;DSS Social (ACRL DSS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:00pm–??:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/243039979783985/&quot;&gt;Que(e)ry at ALA New Orleans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;monday&quot;&gt;Monday&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9:00am–10:00am:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=352359&quot;&gt;Evidence Based Library and Information Practice is…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/ALAAC2018Mon0900am-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:30am–11:30am:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=352258&quot;&gt;Buried in a “Dying” Field: Pessimism, Uncertain Futures, and the LIS job search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/ALAAC2018Mon1030amLISJobSearch-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;OR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=352298&quot;&gt;When to Speak Up, When to Listen: Allyship, Race, and Communication in the Academic Library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/ALAAC2018Mon1030amAllyshipRace-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;OR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=352299&quot;&gt;Open Education Resources (OER): Where Libraries Are and Where We are Going&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/ALAAC2018Mon1030amOER-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:00pm–2:00pm:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=352323&quot;&gt;Effort, Education, Knowledge, Skill and Teaching Recognized: The READ (Reference Effort Assessment Data) Scale at work in Academic, Public &amp;amp; Special Libraries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/ALAAC2018Mon0100pmREADscale-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:00pm–5:00pm:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=352236&quot;&gt;A Library for Everyone: Community Centered Design to Promote Inclusive Librarianship&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/ALAAC2018Mon0400pmCommunity-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tuesday&quot;&gt;Tuesday&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:00am–11:30am:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventscribe.com//2018/ALA-Annual/fsPopup.asp?Mode=presInfo&amp;amp;PresentationID=380141&quot;&gt;Closing General Session featuring Viola Davis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pad.riseup.net/p/ALAAC2018Tues1000amClosing-ViolaDavis-keep&quot;&gt;etherpad link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:sandpie&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Making a Sandstorm instance is kind of pie-in-the-sky as a goal for me at the moment, but I can definitely put the notes on my blog at minimum. If you’re interested in helping with a Sandstorm instance for library workers, let’s talk! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:sandpie&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>ryan</name></author><category term="conferences" /><summary type="html">Where I intend to be for ALAAC2018 and how I think we can make group notes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WA 2017 Week 09: Badges, Type, BibTeX</title><link href="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/weekly-assemblage/wa-2017-week-09" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WA 2017 Week 09: Badges, Type, BibTeX" /><published>2017-03-06T17:01:39-07:00</published><updated>2017-03-06T17:01:39-07:00</updated><id>https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/weekly-assemblage/wa-2017-week-09</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/weekly-assemblage/wa-2017-week-09">&lt;p class=&quot;notice--info&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/weekly-assemblage/weekly-whaaa&quot;&gt;Weekly Whaaa…?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;emily-fords-to-badge-or-not-to-badge-from-yes-to-never-again&quot;&gt;Emily Ford’s “To badge or not to badge? From ‘yes’ to ‘never again’”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://crln.acrl.org/content/78/1/20.full&quot;&gt;“To badge or not to badge? From ‘yes’ to ‘never again’”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like this article and appreciate Emily Ford’s perspective here. Oddly enough, we’ve gone ahead with a variant of badging at my college just this semester. It’s really more about flipping the content than a “badging” system, and I think we’re doing it in a way that avoids the pitfalls she’s laid out nicely in this article. At least, I &lt;em&gt;hope&lt;/em&gt; we are. We’re doing assessment, so we’ll find out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pablo-stanleys-the-type-snob&quot;&gt;Pablo Stanley’s “The Type Snob”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thedesignteam.io/the-type-snob-f221969a884b#.or8g97bg6&quot;&gt;The Type Snob (and how to turn into one)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not exactly pro-snob, but I am staunchly in favor of a well-made explainer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vukanjs-bibtex-helper-for-atom&quot;&gt;VukanJ’s “bibtex-helper” for Atom&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I first read Dennis Tenen and Grant Wythoff’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://programminghistorian.org/lessons/sustainable-authorship-in-plain-text-using-pandoc-and-markdown&quot;&gt;Sustainable Authorship in Plain Text using Pandoc and Markdown&lt;/a&gt; lesson at &lt;a href=&quot;http://programminghistorian.org&quot;&gt;The Programming Historian&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve been into the idea of using &lt;a href=&quot;http://pandoc.org/index.html&quot;&gt;Pandoc&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bibtex.org&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;. I haven’t done so extensively—just for the last semester of library school, so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I really like the idea of using simplified citekeys, so I’m putting together a system around this now, as I’m in the middle of a writing project that uses a lot of articles I’m &lt;strong&gt;highly likely&lt;/strong&gt; to use again in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is where VukanJ’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/VukanJ/bibtex-helper&quot;&gt;bibtext-helper&lt;/a&gt; comes in. I’ve taken to using the Atom editor whenever I can, and VukanJ’s tool is basically a set of snippets I can invoke by typing the citation style (e.g. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@inproceedings&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@article&lt;/code&gt;), which prompts Atom to expand the snippet into a citation template with all the appropriate fields for that type of citation. At first I couldn’t figure out how to add it to Atom, since VukanJ’s documentation is…let’s say “light.” I eventually just hit select-all on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/VukanJ/bibtex-helper/blob/master/snippets/bibtex-snippets.cson&quot;&gt;this file&lt;/a&gt;, copied everything, then pasted it into my &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;snippets.cson&lt;/code&gt; file in Atom. At first it didn’t work, so I changed the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;'.text.bibtex'&lt;/code&gt; in line 1 to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;'.text.md'&lt;/code&gt;. Now it sings! I did alter a few things—specifically adding &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@crossref = {}&lt;/code&gt; to the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@inbook&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@incollection&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@inproceedings&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@inreference&lt;/code&gt; snippets, as Nelson H. F. Beebe’s super-helpful &lt;a href=&quot;http://ftp.math.utah.edu/pub/bibnet/bibtex-info.html#crossref&quot;&gt;guide&lt;/a&gt; suggests. I also added &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;address = {}&lt;/code&gt; to the relevant snippets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last few things I’ve written, I used Zotero to collate the info and then Bibdesk to put the citation into my writing. But I profoundly didn’t like how that combination wouldn’t let me change the citekey. Numbers and time aren’t intrinsically meaningful to my mind, so I’d much rather cite something as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@hall_local_and_global&lt;/code&gt; than &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@hall_1989a&lt;/code&gt;. I also didn’t like how the Zotero + Bibdesk citations would seem to arbitrarily decide to force capitalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m thinking I might put up my main bibliography file on Github somewhere, either as part of this site or somewhere else. It’d be nice to be able to refer to those citekeys from anywhere I might be writing or making reading notes. But for now—actually almost a month after I first wrote the paragraphs above—I’m just going to mention this as one the next citation approach I’m exploring.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ryan</name></author><category term="weekly-assemblage" /><category term="badging" /><category term="tech tools" /><category term="type" /><summary type="html">Briefly linking to Emily Ford's article about badges, a short reference about using type on the web, and getting going with a bibliography tool.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WA 2017 Week 01: Journaling, Pedagogy, and Advocating for our Patrons</title><link href="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/weekly-assemblage/wa-2017-week-01" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WA 2017 Week 01: Journaling, Pedagogy, and Advocating for our Patrons" /><published>2017-01-08T01:33:09-07:00</published><updated>2017-01-08T01:33:09-07:00</updated><id>https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/weekly-assemblage/wa-2017-week-01</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/weekly-assemblage/wa-2017-week-01">&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/weekly-assemblage/weekly-whaaa&quot;&gt;Weekly Whaaa…?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;craig-eleys-jekyll-logbook-theme&quot;&gt;Craig Eley’s Jekyll logbook theme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it was due to participating in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://critlib.org/critical-reflection-chat/&quot;&gt;#critlib chat on reflection&lt;/a&gt;, moderated by Lisa Hubbell? Perhaps it was because I miss using DayOne, which I slowly abandoned after they &lt;a href=&quot;http://help.dayoneapp.com/day-one-sync-faq/&quot;&gt;changed how they sync&lt;/a&gt; the files? Perhaps it’s just that I’ve gotten really used to using &lt;a href=&quot;http://programminghistorian.org/lessons/building-static-sites-with-jekyll-github-pages&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, and this is another interesting use of that familiar technology?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any event, I started using Craig Eley’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@craigeley/journaling-with-jekyll-c7065031a33#.q2cqsthkn&quot;&gt;“Trophy Logbook”&lt;/a&gt; theme for Jekyll over the holidays and really appreciate it so far. I even submitted My First Pull Request™, helping organize the tags alphabetically with Liquid rather than strictly chronologically. (I’m going to try to help figure out how to sort by tags frequency, but that’s on the back-burner for probably at least another week.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to try journaling with it—or if you’d just like to give Jekyll a try without your first attempt being public—Eley’s theme works quite well. Craig explains in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@craigeley/journaling-with-jekyll-c7065031a33#.q2cqsthkn&quot;&gt;Medium post&lt;/a&gt; that it’s designed to use tags to track people’s name and categories to track places. For my own use, I’m doing that, but also tracking regular topic tags with the simple blunt strategy of adding &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;0-&lt;/code&gt; before the tag, so they’re all sorted prior to the names. So instead of just writing &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;meta&lt;/code&gt; in the tag field, I’m writing &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;0-meta&lt;/code&gt;. I don’t track physical locations very often, so I’m mostly using categories to track the media I watch or read. I’ve started putting some reading notes in there as well. I’ve been hankering for a place to put reading notes, and having the option of using both the work’s title and topic tags seems like a very promising set-up for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This theme uses Jekyll plugins that make it incompatible with Github Pages—not a bad thing, unless you’re exhibitionist enough to want your journal rendered publicly. If you want a private place to store your journal and perhaps write to it from a different device than your computer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com&quot;&gt;GitLab&lt;/a&gt; lets you have private repos for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bonnie-stuarts-posts-on-antigonish&quot;&gt;Bonnie Stuart’s posts on Antigonish&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonnie Stewart’s last two articles, &lt;a href=&quot;http://theory.cribchronicles.com/2016/11/30/temporarily-embarrassed-millionaires/&quot;&gt;“temporarily embarrassed millionaires”&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://theory.cribchronicles.com/2017/01/07/antigonish-2-0-the-plan/&quot;&gt;“Antigonish 2.0—the plan”&lt;/a&gt;, are giving me some hope and optimism about how librarians and other educators can advocate for everyone in our communities in the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bryan-alexanders-we-make-the-path-by-walking-group-read&quot;&gt;Bryan Alexander’s &lt;em&gt;We Make the Path by Walking&lt;/em&gt; group read&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first of Bonnie Stewart’s two above articles mentions &lt;em&gt;We Make the Road by Walking&lt;/em&gt;, a book by Myles Horton and Paulo Freire. If you haven’t already notice how much of a touchstone Freire has become among instruction librarians, Joshua F. Beatty presented an excellent paper at the 2015 CAPAL conference, which he has &lt;a href=&quot;http://digitalcommons.plattsburgh.edu/lis/7/&quot;&gt;open-access here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;ai ai-open-access&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bryan Alexander up some of the activities on an online group read of &lt;em&gt;We Make the Road by Walking&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://bryanalexander.org/2017/01/05/reading-horton-and-freire-into-2017/&quot;&gt;“Reading Horton and Freire in 2017”&lt;/a&gt;. I’m going to have a busy semester with a lot of reading, but I’m aiming to read this book as well. It’s important to not just acknowledge, but also learn from, histories of what works domestically. Horton’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Highlander_Research_and_Education_Center&quot;&gt;Highlander Folk School&lt;/a&gt; certainly has a history to learn from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;meredith-farkas-never-neutral-critical-librarianship-and-technology&quot;&gt;Meredith Farkas’ “Never Neutral: Critical librarianship and technology”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s great to see that Meredith Farkas’ article on the impossibility of neutrality and the harm perpetuated by failing to advocate for our patrons is reading the readers of &lt;a href=&quot;https://americanlibrariesmagazine.org/2017/01/03/never-neutral-critlib-technology/&quot;&gt;American Libraries Magazine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s short and worth reading in its entirety. Here are a couple excellent quotes that resonate strongly with my week-to-week work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Librarians may not be able to change Google or Facebook, but we can educate our patrons and support the development of the critical-thinking skills they need to navigate an often-biased online world. We can empower our patrons when we help them critically evaluate information and teach them about bias in search engines, social media, and publishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We are not doing our job if we remain neutral when it comes to library technologies. Accepting many of the technologies available to support our missions means accepting technologies that are biased, not accessible, not protective of the privacy of our users, and not easily usable by some of our patrons. A commitment to social justice is a commitment to equal access, which is at the heart of our professional values. We are not being neutral when we advocate for our patrons, but we are being good librarians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>ryan</name></author><category term="weekly-assemblage" /><category term="meta" /><category term="critlib chats" /><category term="neutrality" /><category term="pedagogy" /><summary type="html">Can I make routinely time for these round-up posts this semester? Let's find out, shall we? Links about journaling, pedagogy, and advocating for our patrons.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Critical Reflection #critlib chat</title><link href="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/critical-reflection" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Critical Reflection #critlib chat" /><published>2016-12-18T00:20:10-07:00</published><updated>2016-12-18T00:20:10-07:00</updated><id>https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/critical-reflection</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/critical-reflection">&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;Here’s a post in preparation for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://critlib.org/critical-reflection-chat/&quot;&gt;“Critical Reflection” #critlib chat&lt;/a&gt; moderated by Lisa Hubbell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lisa Hubbell’s commitment to making this chat about critical reflection more accessible to people for whom Twitter isn’t optimal inspired me enough to want to do a “seeding” blog post of my own. The topic itself seems to beg for a different kind of engagement. I’ve got a few different facets of “reflection” in mind, so I’ll try to address all of them here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tools-for-thinking&quot;&gt;Tools for Thinking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prompts work well for me, as do other tools for thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most basic of these prompts was drilled into me while I was on high school newspaper, if not earlier: the old, reliable “who, what, when, where, why, and how?” questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a few more that I believe help nuance those and make our answers more critically reflective:&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:ct&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:ct&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For whom is this accurate, in what ways, and under what conditions?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who does this obscure?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whose participation is left out?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does this way of thinking frame people as passive or active?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How is this useful? What does it help us do in the world?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Seah’s various &lt;a href=&quot;http://davidseah.com/productivity-tools/&quot;&gt;productivity tools&lt;/a&gt; profoundly help reinforce a practice of reflection. Unlike a lot of people who write about productivity, his site and tools don’t trip my spidey sense for boosterism or selling things. He gives the documents away as free downloads! (He does sell pre-printed ones as well.) Instead, between his explanations of the various tools and his own blog about things like his &lt;a href=&quot;http://davidseah.com/tag/ghdr/&quot;&gt;“groundhog resolutions”&lt;/a&gt;, he seems very committed to the idea that review is a (maybe &lt;em&gt;the?&lt;/em&gt;) path to progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like Seah’s phrase “tools for thinking” enough that it’s what I call most of the relevant library handouts I make at my library: simple templates for expanding &amp;amp; narrowing search terms, for brainstorming keywords, that kind of thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-actual-practice&quot;&gt;My Actual Practice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For readings, I take lots of marginal notes. This semester I read Casey Boyle’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://caseyboyle.net/2016/01/16/something-like-a-reading-ethics/&quot;&gt;…something like a reading ethics…&lt;/a&gt;, and I intend to start doing something along those lines from here on out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My reading notes—and all of my notes, really—are &lt;a href=&quot;http://bettermess.com/a-plain-text-primer/&quot;&gt;plain text&lt;/a&gt;, in &lt;a href=&quot;http://programminghistorian.org/lessons/getting-started-with-markdown&quot;&gt;Markdown format&lt;/a&gt;, and stored in Dropbox. That way I can always sync them between whatever computer or device I’m using. I usually use &lt;a href=&quot;http://atom.io&quot;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt; on my laptop or at work, plus &lt;a href=&quot;http://omz-software.com/editorial/&quot;&gt;Editorial&lt;/a&gt; on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plain text synced through Dropbox means that I don’t have to fret about leaving a notebook filled in my insights somewhere. I profoundly enjoy writing by hand, but I don’t enjoy the anxiety that builds up the more I have in a notebook and nowhere else. When I want to go back and somehow do revisions on earlier ideas in plain text, I’ll usually use &lt;a href=&quot;http://criticmarkup.com&quot;&gt;Critic Markup&lt;/a&gt; for most of my jotting-ideas-down writing, or &lt;em&gt;much more rarely&lt;/em&gt; I’ll track changes for more formal writing through &lt;a href=&quot;http://data-lessons.github.io/library-git/&quot;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have a sort of &lt;a href=&quot;http://bulletjournal.com/get-started/&quot;&gt;bullet journal&lt;/a&gt; with plain text files for each month, with the idea that I’ll go back and do some review every night as well as again on weekends. It helps, but I certainly don’t do it as consistently as I’d like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://cirillocompany.de/pages/pomodoro-technique/&quot;&gt;Pomodoro technique&lt;/a&gt; (and time-blocking more generally) also sometimes helps when I need extra push to focus on something that I know I also want to examine critically. Pomodoros seem to give me permission to toggle between the “make stuff!” and “wait, what’s this leading toward?” habits of mind. Beyond just each 30 minute cycle (25 minutes of &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/CTM9dSlIepQ&quot;&gt;GO!!!!!&lt;/a&gt;, 5 minutes reflection), the broader technique also invites more substantive reflection every few hours and at the beginning &amp;amp; end of the day. I’m not great with experiencing time, and therefore &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; not great at estimating time. Since pomodoros turn nicely into time tracking, it’s a practice with many interlocking benefits.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:prowl&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:prowl&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-desired-practice&quot;&gt;My Desired Practice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbooklibrarian.wordpress.com/2016/12/17/critical-reflection-more-on-teachings-and-tools/&quot;&gt;Lisa Hubbell’s second “seeding” post&lt;/a&gt; for this &lt;a href=&quot;http://critlib.org/critical-reflection-chat/&quot;&gt;critlib chat&lt;/a&gt; delves into broader teachings and reflective practices, I’ll mention that Buddhist thought has worked well for me since about high school. I wouldn’t claim to be a practicing Buddhist and don’t really identify as one, just as sort of a long-time beginner or appreciator; I don’t go to a regular meeting place, don’t have a consistent meditation practice, and couldn’t recall the details of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://tricycle.org/magazine/noble-eightfold-path/&quot;&gt;noble eightfold path&lt;/a&gt; or any other fundamental precepts off the top of my head. All the same, Buddhist teachings around liberation, loving kindness, and mindfulness more than merely resonate with me. They help me make sense of the world. They work for me, and they’ve worked for other people I care about deeply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve found helpful things in writings by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lionsroar.com/author/bell-hooks/&quot;&gt;bell hooks&lt;/a&gt; (that’s to her posts at &lt;em&gt;Lion’s Roar&lt;/em&gt; magazine/website, although my introduction to her Buddhism was the &lt;a href=&quot;https://tricycle.org/magazine/agent-change-an-interview-with-bell-hooks/&quot;&gt;“Agent of Change”&lt;/a&gt; article for which Tricycle occasionally lifts its paywall), Shunryu Suzuki’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/oclc/136259&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zen Mind, Beginner’s Mind&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Brad Warner’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/oclc/906010679&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hardcore Zen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and Chade-Meng Tan’s endearingly self-deprecating &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/oclc/757483928&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Search Inside Yourself&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:aw&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:aw&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years ago, when I desperately needed to hear something along its lines, the Back to Work &lt;a href=&quot;http://5by5.tv/b2w/3&quot;&gt;“The Second Arrow”&lt;/a&gt; episode on ADD, Buddhism, and mindfulness was profoundly helpful, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a critlib audience? I really, really recommend listening to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/buddhistgeeks/talking-race-love-and&quot;&gt;“Talking Race, Love, and Liberation” episode of the &lt;em&gt;Buddhist Geeks&lt;/em&gt; podcast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:eaves&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:eaves&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The dialog between the host &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://angelkyodowilliams.com&quot;&gt;Reverend angel Kyodo williams&lt;/a&gt; captures the sort of liberation-seeking, loving kindness practice that I’m working toward making my own critical reflective practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:ct&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I don’t recall seeing these anywhere in particular; they’re sort of a distillation of what I’ve picked up from various types of what I consider “critical theory,” ranging from Cultural Studies to various types of activism to rhetorical analysis. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:ct&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:prowl&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;If you want to get next-level geeky with this, Ugo Landini’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://pomodoro.ugolandini.com&quot;&gt;Pomodoro app for Mac&lt;/a&gt; can sync up with &lt;a href=&quot;http://growl.info&quot;&gt;Growl notifications&lt;/a&gt; and then even to your phone with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prowlapp.com&quot;&gt;Prowl notifications&lt;/a&gt;. Time’s passage can follow you even when you wander away from your keyboard, as long as you carry your phone with you. If you’re like me, you’ll be humbled by how rapidly &amp;amp; repeatedly your monkey mind runs away from your intentions. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:prowl&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:aw&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I feel I’m obligated to also gesture toward whatever second-hand Alan Watts books I read back in high school, but I suspect they’d strike me as pretty &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orientalism#Critical_studies&quot;&gt;Orientalist&lt;/a&gt; if I re-read them now. Choose your own adventure with those. Looking at titles &amp;amp; cover images, it probably included &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/oclc/228493&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Way of Zen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/oclc/35206460&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is It&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:aw&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:eaves&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;It has enough Buddhist terminology that I occasionally felt more like an eavesdropper than a listener, but I kind of feel like that’s an especially productive approach to this topic. It’s good practice to sit with not being centered by a conversation. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:eaves&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>ryan</name></author><category term="critlib chats" /><category term="tools for thinking" /><summary type="html">Critical reflection questions I ask myself and tools I find useful.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WA 2016 Week 32: Lots of Linkage; Comments Have Arrived</title><link href="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/weekly-assemblage/wa-2016-week-32" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WA 2016 Week 32: Lots of Linkage; Comments Have Arrived" /><published>2016-08-14T22:18:40-06:00</published><updated>2016-08-14T22:18:40-06:00</updated><id>https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/weekly-assemblage/wa-2016-week-32</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ryanpatrickrandall.com/weekly-assemblage/wa-2016-week-32">&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/weekly-assemblage/weekly-whaaa&quot;&gt;Weekly Whaaa…?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lots-of-linkage&quot;&gt;Lots of Linkage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a handful of links that I either shared or meant to share on Twitter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rachael Neu linked to Richard Van Heertum’s “How Objective is Objectivity?” article in &lt;a href=&quot;http://escholarship.org/uc/search?entity=gseis_interactions;volume=1;issue=2&quot;&gt;UCLA InterActions journal&lt;/a&gt; recently in a list-serv. I’m eagerly awaiting reading that article, but in the meanwhile wanted to share the link to the InterActions overall. It looks like a great, open access&lt;i class=&quot;ai ai-open-access&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, peer-reviewed LIS and education publication that focuses on information studies, not strictly information &lt;em&gt;science.&lt;/em&gt; In other words, it’s very much up my alley!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of open access, I was very intrigued by Archambault, Côté, Struck, and Voorons’ note &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.1science.com/oanumbr.html&quot;&gt;Research Impact of Paywalled versus Open Access Papers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;i class=&quot;ai ai-open-access&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scholarworks.umass.edu/jitpc2010/1/&quot;&gt;Conference Proceedings of JITP 2010: The Politics of Open Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;ai ai-open-access&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; is online and open access. I found that while searching for a copy of John Sullivan’s “Free, Open Source Software Advocacy as a Social Justice Movement: The Discourse of Digital Rights in the 21st Century” article, which I’m still very much looking forward to reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Library Juice Press recently posted an interview with &lt;a href=&quot;http://libraryjuicepress.com/blog/?p=5350&quot;&gt;Dr. Annie Downey, author of &lt;em&gt;Critical Information Literacy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a great read and makes me look forward to getting &lt;del&gt;my grubby paws &lt;/del&gt;my &lt;em&gt;strenuously professional hands&lt;/em&gt; on a copy of the book that I can annotate for my very own!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a fun &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/adzebill/status/759226657194516480&quot;&gt;bread closing taxonomy&lt;/a&gt;. I hope to eventually work it into our information literacy for the sciences somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tara Robertson and Jenna Freedman moderated a #critlib Twitter conversation on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://critlib.org/ethics-of-digitization/&quot;&gt;ethics of digitization&lt;/a&gt;. I wasn’t able to participate directly (only chiming in with a couple half-formed thoughts well afterward) but it looked great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comments-have-arrived&quot;&gt;Comments Have Arrived&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve long wanted to add comments to the site without making people sign up for &lt;em&gt;yet another&lt;/em&gt; service, as is required by most ways of adding comments to static sites (i.e. those made with &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and similar site generators). So I was super excited when I saw that &lt;a href=&quot;https://mademistakes.com&quot;&gt;Michael Rose&lt;/a&gt; had added &lt;a href=&quot;http://staticman.net&quot;&gt;Staticman&lt;/a&gt; to the newest version of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/&quot;&gt;Minimal Mistakes&lt;/a&gt; theme! The present site is still running on a much older version, but I managed to get the comments working and he was kind enough to help me figure out how to make them display properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re very welcome to submit a comment. I will of course moderate them, which Staticman cleverly allows by making use of GitHub’s branching feature. I’m excited by the prospect of this site becoming more collegial and interactive! &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:tdr-sissy&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:tdr-sissy&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:tdr-sissy&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Simultaneously, I’m not above wielding the moderation hammer with all the wanton glee of the Designers Republic’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://thedesignersrepublic.bigcartel.com/product/sissy-poster-3d&quot;&gt;Sissy&lt;/a&gt;. Cheers! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:tdr-sissy&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>ryan</name></author><category term="weekly-assemblage" /><category term="meta" /><summary type="html">Many open access links plus excitement about adding comments to the site.</summary></entry></feed>